<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_us"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://harshit211997.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://harshit211997.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_us" /><updated>2021-11-26T14:46:37+00:00</updated><id>https://harshit211997.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Harshit Kumar</title><author><name>Harshit</name></author><entry><title type="html">How to plan for a solo Darjeeling trip</title><link href="https://harshit211997.github.io/how-to-plan-for-a-solo-darjeeling-trip/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to plan for a solo Darjeeling trip" /><published>2021-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://harshit211997.github.io/how-to-plan-for-a-solo-darjeeling-trip</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://harshit211997.github.io/how-to-plan-for-a-solo-darjeeling-trip/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;places-to-visit&quot;&gt;Places to visit&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darjeeling is a beautiful city with cheerful crowds in markets and pleasant views of Mt. Kilimanjaro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sunrise-from-tiger-hill&quot;&gt;Sunrise from Tiger Hill&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sunrise.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;sunrise&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tiger Hill is the highest point in Darjeeling with best views to Mt. Kilimanjaro. This place is so popular that they have recently started charging Rs. 50 as a ticket price just to visit this area. They are even building a 4 story top building just for everyone to see the sunrise better from this place. Make sure to check google weather prediction to make sure the day is clear though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, you need to wake up early in the morning 3:30 - 4 a.m.(Some might say it’s still night at that point :P), catch a shared cab from one of the taxi stands and get there in about an hour right when it’s sunrise. Make sure to cover your neck head and ears though as it’ll be chilly out there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;walk-around-in-chowk-bazaar&quot;&gt;Walk around in Chowk Bazaar&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/chowk_bazaar.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;chowk_bazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be considered as the centre of Darjeeling. This is a huge area with children playing around, people sitting in benches with music playing sometimes in the Open Air Theatre located here. There is the &lt;strong&gt;Mall Road&lt;/strong&gt; here as well if you want to explore what the local market has to offer(mostly for souvenir purposes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, in general. It’s a pretty good idea to take some time to familiarize yourself with the area on what the transportation looks like when you first visit a new place. You can find bikes on rent and taxi drivers to ask the costs to nearby places. You can also find buses too around here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s are a few viewpoints around the back of this place which has some amazing views of Mt. Kilimanjaro, and which I think are one of the most beatiful views in all of Darjeeling(controversial, I know! I liked this even better than the Tiger Hill view point). I would recommend getting a place close to this and walking here in the morning to get some excercise in(If you’re into that grind)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;batasia-loop&quot;&gt;Batasia loop&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/batasia.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;batasia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an engineering marvel which was desined to allow trains to climb a steep 140 ft! You can take a Toy train ride from Darjeeling to Ghum and back and look at insides of a steam engine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/steam_engine.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;steam_engine&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-trip-to-mirik&quot;&gt;Day trip to Mirik&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mirik.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mirik&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;peace-pagora&quot;&gt;Peace Pagora&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/peace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;peace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>harshit</name></author><category term="Travel" /><category term="solo" /><summary type="html">Places to visit Darjeeling is a beautiful city with cheerful crowds in markets and pleasant views of Mt. Kilimanjaro.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://harshit211997.github.io/assets/images/toy_train.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://harshit211997.github.io/assets/images/toy_train.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor</title><link href="https://harshit211997.github.io/powerful-things-markdown-editor/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor" /><published>2020-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://harshit211997.github.io/powerful-things-markdown-editor</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://harshit211997.github.io/powerful-things-markdown-editor/">&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with writing in Markdown, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you’ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we’re using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-formatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;strike through&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;==highlight==&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-code-blocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using Rouge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reference-lists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quick brown jumped over the lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-html&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you’re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Markdown editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here’s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>harshit</name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="tutorial" /><summary type="html">There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://harshit211997.github.io/assets/images/4.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://harshit211997.github.io/assets/images/4.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>